Mohammad El Prince

Mississauga, ON | 519-760-1559 | mohammad-elprince@proton.me <u>LinkedIn | Github | Portfolio</u>

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full Stack Software Engineer with experience in JavaScript and Python based programming. With a background in mechanical engineering and operations, I have a can-do attitude and bring strong skills in problem-solving, communication and collaboration. As a lifelong learner, I continuously work on growing my technical knowledge. I enjoy tackling challenges head-on and crafting creative solutions to real-world problems. My belief in the power of teamwork guides me in achieving exceptional results.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, React.is, Next.is, FastAPI, Scss, SQL, VSCode, Git

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

WriteWell - GitHub | Demo | Live

WriteWell is a full-stack app that enables bloggers to share, edit, and delete blogs.

- Built with Next.js for the front end and styled with scss.
- Employed Next.js routing ability to construct endpoints for API requests.
- Utilized MySQL as the database, which is deployed on AWS RDS.
- Deployed images to AWS S3 and linked them to the database.

Portfolio - GitHub | Demo | Live

A digital showcase of my professional journey, highlighting my skills and projects.

- Employed HTML, CSS, and JavaScript showcasing my abilities to learn and in front-end web development and design.
- Incorporated interactive elements and animation using JS and CSS
- Maintained DRY coding following best practices in all the project files

GPT-3 Intro - GitHub | Demo | Live

A landing page created to describe GPT-3 technology that provides a brief introduction about this modern AI technology.

- Built with ReactJS and CSS styling showcasing an appealing user experience.
- Utilized BEM (Block Element Modifier) technique to relate JSX elements to styling.
- Deployed JSON server as the backend server.

Budget Tracker CLI - GitHub | Demo

A command-line application designed to help you manage your finances and track your expenses easily.

- Employed python scripts and functions and maintained DRY coding
- Utilized SQLAlchemy for database management.
- Implemented the rich library for a user-friendly CL interface.

RECENT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Amazon, Hamilton/St. Thomas/London/Mississauga, ON

05/2021 - Present

Lead Fulfillment Associate/Field Quality Assurance

- Manage 50+ Associates across Amazon Robotics (AR) floor and inventory workstations.
- Monitor the health of four Amazon Robotics floors for optimal productivity and safe operation.
- Train Level1 Leads and provide coverage for other managers.

University of Guelph, Guelph, ON

01/2019 - 05/2021

Teaching/Research Assistant

- Lectured large groups of students (75 150 students) on fundamental engineering courses and proctored exams.
- Conducted experimental and theoretical research in the areas of gas wells and safety of nuclear power plants.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Full Stack Web Development, Python and JavaScript online program	02/2023 - 10/2023
University of Guelph, Guelph, ON Master of Engineering — Mechanical Engineering (course-based)	01/2019 – 02/2021
King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals, Dhahran, KSA Master of Science — Mechanical Engineering (Thesis-based) Bachelor of Science — Mechanical Engineering (course-based)	09/2016 – 12/2018 01/2012 – 05/2016